<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blog.altartist.art</id>
    <title>Alt Bright Official Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T02:45:54.997Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.altartist.art"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://blog.altartist.art/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Comment on artworks and anything else I wanna comment on here.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://blog.altartist.art/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://blog.altartist.art/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2025, Alt Bright Official Blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comment on Undertale]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.altartist.art/Undertale/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.altartist.art/Undertale/">
        </link>
        <updated>2025-09-19T14:16:32.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="overall-rating-2-10">Overall Rating <strong>2 /10</strong></h1>
<p>I've played it twice, I first played it when I was 13, and yesterday, now I am an adult, I played again.<br>
But this time, I decide to give it only 2 stars.</p>
<h1 id="music-9-10">Music <strong>9 /10</strong></h1>
<p>As we all know I am a music lover and learner, and, of course, a music researcher! So no matter what the works are, one of the things I VALUE most must be MUSIC!</p>
<p>The music style is electricity and 8-bit, I think it's deeply retro, especially 8-bit. It always reminds me of those classicial games such as Super Mario, Maple Story, etc.</p>
<p>In Undertale, obviously the soundtrack is nice! I like Toby Fox so much, because he is so brilliant that not only he can code, but also he can make music.<br>
The melody of it seem that so similair, It seems that Fox is a little lazy, lol.But I don't really think so. Some similair melodies, they're very unified, make the overall theme so clear. That's so clever.<br>
And, it is a pixel game. Pixel style always remind people of a word, RETRO. So the repetitive melodies create this perfectly.</p>
<p>Also, do you know MEMZ? It's a trojan horse created for Microsoft computers.<br>
If your computer infected with this virus, a pixel Nyan Cat will appear in your screen, with brainwashing 8-bit music.<br>
So 8-bit style can deeply let people to remember it.</p>
<p>So, the music style fascinates me deeply, Although it's easy to get tired of it if you hear it too much. This is the biggest disadvantage of this sort of music.</p>
<h1 id="art-style-5-10">Art Style <strong>5 /10</strong></h1>
<p>Yeah it's a pixel game, it looks so retro.<br>
And because the story is about human-beings and monsters, with a very ancient historical background, so I think using pixel style is a very very brilliant choice!!! This can well strengthen the background of this story.<br>
Morever, I can feel a sense of fantasy, lonely, and a fairy tale.<br>
That's so great.</p>
<p>But I only give it 5 stars instead of full stars.The reason is simple, I also think some scenes are a little monotonous, it's easy to get tired of it too. Maybe it's the biggest disadvantage of pixel style.<br>
And, I think it can also have different scenes. Give an example, in Snowdin Town, I think it can have more scenes such as riverside (although it really has), more differnet sorts of houses (because it is called Snowdin Town).<br>
But unfortunately, there are only large forests in Snowdin Town.</p>
<p>If a game's scenes always a bit similar, players are absolutely bored of it soon.</p>
<h1 id="game-mechanic-1-10">Game Mechanic <strong>1 /10</strong></h1>
<p>I admit that the game mechanic is very novel and innovative.<br>
But it still has a fatal problem.<br>
Because its particularity, I'll talk about this in detail below, with the script.<br>
Now let's talk alone about it.</p>
<h2 id="auto-archive">Auto archive</h2>
<p><img src="https://blog.altartist.art/post-images/1758339186328.png" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
Let's check this image above. It's the scene when Frisk left the ruins and came to Snowdin Town. And when I played there, my computer got wrong and the game crashed by itself, so obviously I didn't save the archive.<br>
Maybe it's because I've played too much The Witcher 3 (The games are like it all have auto archieve) , I would think that it would automatically save the game if I arrived at a new location.<br>
But unfortunately, it doesn't have this function.<br>
And don't forget it is a RPG, this function is very important.</p>
<h2 id="skipping-dialogue">Skipping Dialogue</h2>
<p>As a RPG, it absolutely has many dialogues.<br>
But you don't have to read every word the NPC says.<br>
And... Logically speaking, a conversation should be displayed immediately after pressing the Enter key.<br>
But this game seems not to do it.</p>
<h2 id="monster-refresh">Monster Refresh</h2>
<p>Oh my god I must complain about this.<br>
Emmm... why there were always monsters pestered me as I walked on the map? I think the refresh frequency is too high.</p>
<h2 id="teleport-point">Teleport point</h2>
<p>As we all know there are some different scenes in Undertale, but to my surprised it doesn't have teleport points...<br>
Having teleport points is very important for RPG. Because if you feel a little boring about the game such as you can't clear the level, you must want to come back to the places you've visited before,or you forgot to take some important items in the previous map.<br>
If the game has teleport points, you can quickly come back instead of walking to here...</p>
<p>Now let me talk about an important issue.<br>
You'll meet a spider called Muffet, and you must &quot;fight&quot; with her.<br>
But it's difficult to defeat her if you dont have some special snacks for her.<br>
And when I first played there, well I'm not good at playing games so it spent me a very long time to clear the level. The biggest reason was I didn't know those special snacks should be given to her... Because I need to restore my HP, I ate it in advance...<br>
You may say you can directly  kill her, or risist her attack. But I wanna say, is it very meaningful? If the auther wants to reflect the special gameplay of the game, I think this is very far-fetched.</p>
<h1 id="story-1-10">Story <strong>1 /10</strong></h1>
<p>To be honest, this game is highly recommended by my friend. She told me that its story is very very nice. Not only her, medias, people on the Internet, even IGN all think so.<br>
But I don't care, I only hear my heart. I will not change my subjective opinion based on the opinions of others or even so-called professional rating media as IGN, IMDb.</p>
<p>If I describe this story, it would be extremely childish, pretentious, and overly preachy!</p>
<h2 id="first">First</h2>
<p>The characterization is almost very weak.<br>
That means I can't feel any souls of the characters. It seems that signs with words hanging on their faces, and when I met a new character, I always felt that it didn't a character in front of me, it should be the auther... It seems that all the characters are actually just the author himself.</p>
<p>And lots of people all think the story is so nice just because it has many endings?<br>
In my opinion, I only think it only has 3 endings. First, killed all characters. Second, killed nobody. Third, killed a little.<br>
The other endings are just extra insignificant things.</p>
<p>And... do you really think these should be called as A deep and philosophical story?<br>
Too CHILDISH!!!!!!<br>
Because the world is not black and white, and everyone should be complicated. We need to know someone's motivation for doing a thing.</p>
<p>As mentioned before, these characters have no soul, because there is basically no characterization, which is very interesting.<br>
So, if player determind to kill anyone he/she met, what reason do the monsters to condemn he/she?<br>
This is like a self-directed performance. But I am a player, so why should I act with you?</p>
<h2 id="second">Second</h2>
<p>Yeah it's not only a RPG but also a MetaGame!<br>
Don't you think it's contradictory?<br>
Logically speaking, RPG requires players to fully immerse themselves in the role, let alone a fairy tale-like story in such a fantasy world.<br>
But what's the MetaGame?!<br>
I don't wanna explain it here, please go to check Wikipedia.</p>
<h2 id="third">Third</h2>
<p>I really don't think monsters in it have soul. At least the auther let them DON'T HAVE SOUL.<br>
The reason is simple. Lots of people including the auther all think that monsters are also independent individuals and they also desire peace with humans, so we can definitely communicate with them and we can influence them with love.<br>
But I really don't think so. It's so unreasonable. It's so childish!</p>
<p>First of all, seeking common ground while reserving differences is difficult to achieve in reality, so why can every monster be persuaded? Why do they always have the same ideas?<br>
And why can the protagonist influence them?</p>
<p>If I have to give a reason, I can only say that the author has created monsters that are completely lacking in subject consciousness and their own standpoints, while he himself stands high above the human perspective, like a savior saving them.<br>
But this in itself is unequal.</p>
<p>Morever, this game is full of too many long-winded sermons, but as mentioned before, the characterization of the monsters is almost non-existent, and the whole thing is very confusing. As an RPG, it is completely impossible to get into the role.</p>
<p>So I don't know why lots of people all think it is a nice, perfect story.<br>
From an RPG perspective, it doesn't qualify.<br>
From a Meta perspective, it doesn't qualify too.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comment on The legend of 1900]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.altartist.art/The-legend-of-1900/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.altartist.art/The-legend-of-1900/">
        </link>
        <updated>2025-09-09T09:06:03.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="overall-rating-4-10">Overall Rating <strong>4 /10</strong></h1>
<p>Because it's a movie about Music, so I had a great interest in it.<br>
But when I really watched it, oh my god, my feeling is like a roller coaster.<br>
The rating, at first was 8, then became 6... Finally, I rate it <strong>3</strong>.</p>
<p>In general, the movie is good,but absolutely not can be called <strong>PERFECT</strong>.Many disadvantages in it.<br>
There is no doubt that the director's shooting style, camera movement, scenery, colors, etc. are all very good. But it still has many disadvantages.</p>
<h1 id="casting-3-10">Casting <strong>3 /10</strong></h1>
<p>First, there is a very huge problem with the casting of the movie. I'm not saying Tim Roth's acting is bad, but he's really not suited to this role. I think 1900 should be a shy, with very few words,when you first see him, you will immediately feel that he is a person who has been on the ship since he was born, a person who is isolated from the world, dares not speak, and keeps a distance from the world.<br>
But Tim's look can't make me feel like that. I think he is more like a shrewd businessman. Anyway, definitely not a musician with a special aura who is isolated from the world.<br>
So when I watched it,I always feel out of place.</p>
<p>The other actors are well cast.But 1900 is the main character of this movie,the MAIN character's casting is not suitable, so I only give its casting 3 stars.</p>
<h1 id="fonts-1-10">Fonts <strong>1 /10</strong></h1>
<p>I MUST say about this topic, because I am a designer.<br>
As we all know, at the beginning of a movie, there are always the main characters' actor/actresses' names, and the movie's name.</p>
<p>Regardless of whether the plot of this movie is too far-fetched, it describes the story of a legendary &quot;musician&quot; who has passed away, the way of recollection, and perhaps the nostalgia for the past.<br>
But the font of the beginning of the movie actually uses <strong>cursive</strong>!!!<br>
Is this a light and romantic movie?<br>
I'm curious about it,why the director used such fonts ...<br>
This is not SERIOUS at all!</p>
<p>In my opinion, movies'topics like this, must use atmospheric and serious fonts, like Times New Roman.<br>
Or, if you use wrong fonts, your works will immediately become disjointed and inconsistent, and with a strong sense of separation.</p>
<h1 id="soundtrack-5-10">Soundtrack <strong>5 /10</strong></h1>
<p>Have to say, the music is so nice! Especially its melody.<br>
But, because it is a movie about MUSIC, MUSICIAN, so I think the requirements for music should be higher, isn't that too much?<br>
Obviously, the soul of the movie is PIANO, but the soundtrack is too monotonous, It emphasizes the melody of the right hand too much and dilutes the melody of the left hand. So I quickly developed visual fatigue with the soundtrack.<br>
Because the structure of the music is too monotonous and lacks layering. Even piano music shouldn't be like this.</p>
<p>And... If you have interest in composing or music production, you must use FL Studio or Logic Pro. In softwares like these, a song is made up of many tracks. If you don't want your music to be monotonous, then there must be many tracks.</p>
<h1 id="story-2-10">Story <strong>2 /10</strong></h1>
<p>Without a doubt, I think Max is a very good person. He can always trust 1900 and be his only friend. I think this is very precious.<br>
And obviously 1900 is more talented than him, at least that's what the story wants to say, but Max doesn't envy him for this, which is very rare.<br>
Take myself as an example, because I am so brilliant, my friends of many years have parted ways with me, and the old people who have accomplished nothing will also be jealous of me. This is how I spent my adolescence.<br>
So I give one more star only for Max.</p>
<p>But the story is just a f**king laughing, childish, and overly didactic story.That's all.</p>
<h2 id="first">First</h2>
<p>As a music/piano learner and researcher, I am very clearly about it. No matter how talented you are, you can't learn to play the piano just by listening to music. If playing the piano is so easy, why aren't there so many musicians in the world?<br>
So just based on this point, it can be seen that the director did not understand music at all, and did not seem to want to study it specifically for making a movie about music.<br>
In a sense, such behavior is a disgrace to music and pianists.</p>
<p>Also, the film seems to be very interested in showing 1900's ability to improvise. That's so good. Yeah that's right! It would be cool if a person could improvise and express his or her mood freely with an instrument.<br>
But that's very very difficult.<br>
Improvisation relies heavily on chords and accumulation. Basic chords must be learned through books and etudes, as well as melodies.<br>
Improvisation requires a very high level of comprehensive ability, and I absolutely do not believe that someone who only stays on a boat and listens to music can improvise music for no apparent reason.</p>
<p>Moreover, the director seems to have absolutely no understanding of the piano. Playing fast does not equal playing well. If that is the case, then what is the meaning of Chopin's existence?</p>
<h2 id="second">Second</h2>
<p>We all know that great artists such as Yves Saint Laurent and Van Gogh(and me)must have had a life as colorful and legendary as fireworks.<br>
Because of his experience that is completely different from that of the rest of the world and his strong perception, he was able to write a shocking epic. Even if he is gifted, he must be subject to learning and guidance.</p>
<p>But the movie seems to have completely forgotten this point, and glossed over 1900's early life in a passing moment, as if he was inexplicably struck by talent and then began to compose impromptu music.<br>
This completely dilutes the legendary color, but instead strengthens the feeling that 1900 is a fictional character in the movie.</p>
<p>So... I can say, 1900 is absolutely a fictional character created by Max.</p>
<p>Just based on the above two points, this story has nothing to do with being a GOOD story.</p>
<h2 id="third">Third</h2>
<p>At the end of the movie, 1900 and the old ship were blown up in the sea. It really is the end of an era!<br>
Most people think that 1900 is very pure and his death is very legendary.<br>
But I dont think so.<br>
I think he got killed in the bombing purely because he was a coward, not because he was a musician who did not conform to the world.</p>
<p>First of all, have you ever thought about this question: Do you think 1900 really exists? Is he really a human being?<br>
I think he didn't exist, and, absolutely not a human being.<br>
Because he is not social.</p>
<p>So I am more inclined to believe that 1900 does not exist in essence, which explains why only Max found him in the dilapidated old ship in the end.</p>
<p>To be honest, what attracted me most in the beginning of this movie was the ethereal character of 1900. I always thought that he was unwilling to leave the ship even if he was blown up because he found the world to be secular and totally incompatible with his pure and innocent musical world.<br>
However, the more I looked at it, I realized that this was not the case at all!</p>
<p>At the end of the movie, 1900 gave a long, very preachy speech, much like those damn teachers in school.<br>
He said, <em>In all that sprawlling city, there was everything except an end... They are(keys) not infinite, you are infinite... Did you see the streets? Just the streets, there were thousands of them...</em></p>
<p>Perhaps the director felt that this passage was full of philosophical meaning, which directly sublimated the theme of the film.<br>
But I think this paragraph directly destroyed 1900's character and made the theme of the whole story ridiculous and childish!!!</p>
<p>I just think he is cowardly and afraid of change. To be honest, I look down on such people. They have no courage, they will only surrender. They are just cowards and have nothing to do with transcending the mundane!<br>
1900's rejection of land was based on the fact that he never thought he would get it.</p>
<h1 id="summary">Summary</h1>
<p>So, I think this is a pseudo-musical movie, and it is very superficial and very insincere.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>